A Guide to the Fairfax County Road Petitions, 1844-1908
Fairfax Circuit Court Historic Records Center
- 1882 (Box-folder RP-166)
  Road from Pohick Road through Lee Chapel to Road leading from Burke's Station
- August, 1882 (Box-folder RP-167)
  Road from Ridge Road to the Turnpike leading to the city
- November, 1882 (Box-folder RP-168)
  Continue county road to outside gate of Sycamore Farm
- May, 1882 (Box-folder RP-169)
  Change: Road bed of Germantown Road
- October, 1882 (Box-folder RP-170)
  Road through land of Thomas Carper and the Rocky Run to Old Union Church
- November, 1882 (Box-folder RP-171)
  Change: Fox's Mill Road from Difficult Bridge to Waple's Mill
- June, 1882 (Box-folder RP-172)
  Unnamed
- May, 1882 (Box-folder RP-173)
  Intersection of Herndon and Dranesville Roads to Leesburg Turnpike
- June, 1882 (Box-folder RP-174)
  Change: road leading from Union Mills Road to Clifton
- July, 1883 (Box-folder RP-175)
  Change: Hunter's Mill Road at the hickory tree corner to Thorton's land
- May, 1883 (Box-folder RP-176)
  Road from McPherson's farm to the Waples Mill Road
- May, 1883 (Box-folder RP-177)
  Road to take the place of Garner's Mill Road
- June, 1883 (Box-folder RP-178)
  Road through Salsbury's land
- July, 1883 (Box-folder RP-179)
  Road from Wolf Run Shoals Road to Ox Road, opposite of Arundel's Tavern
- May, 1884 (Box-folder RP-180)
  Road connecting the Old Leesburg Road to the Leesburg Turnpike
- May, 1884 (Box-folder RP-181)
  Road from the Occoquan Bridge to Elk Horn Branch
- July, 1884 (Box-folder RP-182)
  Road from Telegraph Road to a point on Hooes Road
- March, 1884 (Box-folder RP-183)
  Change: Keene Mill Road
- June, 1884 (Box-folder RP-184)
  Road leading from Centreville to Manassas to Clifton Station
- September, 1884 (Box-folder RP-185)
  Change: "Lemon Road" running from Middle Turnpike to Falls Church and Lewinsville Roads
- 1884 (Box-folder RP-186)
  Vienna & Andrew Chapel Road
- April, 1884 (Box-folder RP-187)
  Road beginning at Little River Turnpike to the Falls Church Road
- November, 1884 (Box-folder RP-188)
  Road from the Blacksmith Shop of Horace Gibson on the Little River Turnpike to Falls Church Road at Mills Crossing Road
- September, 1885 (Box-folder RP-189)
  Stone's Old Mill Road
- October, 1885 (Box-folder RP-190)
  Road commencing at Vale...from Fairfax Court House to Dranesville
- April, 1885 (Box-folder RP-191)
  Change: Road leading from Old Braddock Road to Clifton
- July, 1885 (Box-folder RP-192)
  Road from C.W. Dey road to Ox Road
- June, 1885 (Box-folder RP-193)
  Change: Road leading from Old Colchester Road to Fairfax Station
- May, 1885 (Box-folder RP-194)
  Road near the house of John and Thomas Clarke to the Lawyers Road
- July, 1885 (Box-folder RP-195)
  Location of Pole Road running from Pool Run to James Hunter's Gate
- November, 1886 (Box-folder RP-196)
  Open portion of New Market Road
- December, 1886 (Box-folder RP-197)
  Change: Hunter's Mill Road leading to Lawyers Road
- February, 1886 (Box-folder RP-198)
  Road from Herndon Chantilly Road the the Valley Road
- February, 1886 (Box-folder RP-199)
  Point on Hampton Road at Sandy Run to Hampton Road
- December, 1886 (Box-folder RP-200)
  Road passing through the Middle Turnpike
- November, 1886 (Box-folder RP-201)
  Change: Road on R. C. Jones' land
- October, 1886 (Box-folder RP-202)
  Change: Road running from Washington, Ohio and Western Railway near Vienna
- April, 1886 (Box-folder RP-203)
  Road from Lawyers Road to County Road to Herndon
- July, 1886 (Box-folder RP-204)
  Road from John Jackson's land to the Gum Spring and Wolcott Road
- March, 1886 (Box-folder RP-205)
  Road from Alexandria Pike to the Georgetown Pike
- 1886 (Box-folder RP-206)
  Road from Braddock Road to the land of Georgine Martin
- September, 1886 (Box-folder RP-207)
  County road leading from Old Union Church to Rocky Run
- April, 1886 (Box-folder RP-208)
  Road from the new road to "Lee Chapel", to Burkes Station, passing through the land of Hannah Burke
- April, 1886 (Box-folder RP-209)
  Change: "Detwiler Road" from Clifton to Centreville Road
- May, 1886 (Box-folder RP-210)
  Change: Clifton and Yates Ford Road to avoid a heavy grade
- June, 1886 (Box-folder RP-211)
  Road through the land of William Harris
- September, 1886 (Box-folder RP-212)
  Road from New Guinea Road to a point on the land of B. Skinner
- 1887 (Box-folder RP-213)
  Clifton and Centreville
- April, 1887 (Box-folder RP-214)
  Change: Road leading from Old Church Road to the Herndon Road
- October, 1887 (Box-folder RP-215)
  Road from point on Backlick Road (Old Gallows Road) to Backlick Road
- July, 1887 (Box-folder RP-216)
  Re-open west end of New Market Road
- February, 1887 (Box-folder RP-217)
  Open a road from Charles Thornton's lands to Berks Station
- March, 1887 (Box-folder RP-218)
  Change: Road leading from Dranesville to Herndon
- June, 1887 (Box-folder RP-219)
  Road from the Pole Road in Mount Vernon district to Long Branch Station on the A & F Railroad to Backlick Road
- February, 1887 (Box-folder RP-220)
  Road from the Telegraph Road to Old County Road at John Henderson's Corner
- August, 1887 (Box-folder RP-221)
  Road from the Little River Turnpike to the Annandale and Old Tavern Road leading towards Washington
- October, 1887 (Box-folder RP-222)
  Change: Willow Spring Road on property of Col. E. White
- November, 1887 (Box-folder RP-223)
  Unknown
- October, 1887 (Box-folder RP-224)
  From the farm of W.H. Snowden to the "County road" leading from "Little Hunting Creek" to Accotink and Alexandria Highway
- June, 1887 (Box-folder RP-225)
  Road from Little River Turnpike to the Braddock Road
- November, 1887 (Box-folder RP-226)
  Road on a point near bridge on Falls Church Road to the Little River Turnpike
- September, 1887 (Box-folder RP-227)
  Widen the road leading from Jenkin's Corner to Andrew Chapel
- July, 1888 (Box-folder RP-228)
  County Road from the middle of Alexandria Pike to Alexandria Line
- April, 1888 (Box-folder RP-229)
  Point on River Road to the Potomac River
- October, 1888 (Box-folder RP-230)
  Change: Part of County Road known as Colchester Road near Doddridge Lee
- 1888 (Box-folder RP-231)
  Road from Braddock Road to Warrenton Pike
- 1888 (Box-folder RP-232)
  Road from Lincolnville County Road to East Falls Church Depot
- 1888 (Box-folder RP-233)
  Road from Occoquan to Colchester
- June, 1888 (Box-folder RP-234)
  Road report on the Little River Turnpike
- September, 1888 (Box-folder RP-235)
  Report on road from Gum Springs to Mt. Vernon
- July, 1888 (Box-folder RP-236)
  Road from Vienna to Hunter's Mill, County Road
- 1888 (Box-folder RP-237)
  Road from Money's Corner on the Lawyer's Road to Thorton (Wheile) Station
- 1888 (Box-folder RP-238)
  Road from Herndon and Detwiler Road to Dunlop's Gate
- 1888 (Box-folder RP-239)
  Road from Bull Run to the Turnpike at J. Well's Corner
- November, 1889 (Box-folder RP-240)
  Road from Leesburg Pike to Carlin Springs
- 1889
  Road extension of Mutersbaugh Road
- October, 1889 (Box-folder RP-242)
  Road from the Georgetown Road to the road leading from the turnpike to Dunn Loring
- 1889 (Box-folder RP-243)
  Road leading from the Braddock Road to the Guinea Road near Long Branch
- 1889 (Box-folder RP-244)
  Road from Ball's Ford on Bull Run to Newmarket Road
- December, 1889 (Box-folder RP-245)
  Road from Little River Pike to Ox Road
- January, 1889 (Box-folder RP-246)
  Road from the land of John Mutersbaugh to the public road leading from Chain Bridge to Falls Church
- 1889 (Box-folder RP-247)
  Change: Road leading from Clifton to the Colchester Road
- October, 1889 (Box-folder RP-248)
  Road from the corner of Ely and Sarner, ending near the Newton Estate
- November, 1889 (Box-folder RP-249)
  Road leading from Episcopal Theological Seminary to Bailey's Crossroads to a post in the line of Terrett
- April, 1890 (Box-folder RP-250)
  Road from the Braddock Road to the Little River Turnpike
- February, 1890 (Box-folder RP-251)
  Change: the new road from Hooes Road to Telegraph Road to the Telegraph Road
- November, 1890 (Box-folder RP-252)
  Change: county road from Waples Mill across the land of A. B. Millard
- October, 1890 (Box-folder RP-253)
  Road from Elgin's school house to the Yates Ford Road
- August, 1890 (Box-folder RP-254)
  Road commencing at Bull Run...to the Centreville and Manassas Road
- August, 1890 (Box-folder RP-255)
  Widen road near Horse Pen Bridge on the Chantilly and Herndon Road
- November, 1890 (Box-folder RP-256)
  Widen county road where it crosses Difficult Run, near Leigh and Beal's (formerly Jackson's) Mill
- March, 1890 (Box-folder RP-257)
  Road survey of Accotink Pike
- RP-258 (Box-folder RP-258)
  Change: Road at Pitman's Mill for the erection of a bridge over Great Rock Cedar Run
- April, 1890 (Box-folder RP-259)
  Change: road leading from Walter's Mill to Freedom Hill
- April-May, 1890 (Box-folder RP-260)
  Change: county road known as the Falls Church Road - from Fairfax Court House to Falls Church
- July, 1890 (Box-folder RP-261)
  Change: road from bridge over Difficult Run at Hunter's Mill to Hunter's Mill Store
- March, 1891 (Box-folder RP-262)
  Extend Maple Avenue in Vienna to Flint Hill Cemetery
- September, 1891 (Box-folder RP-263)
  Change: Sawmill Road
- November, 1891 (Box-folder RP-264)
  Discontinue portion of Ox Road from the north line of George Howard's land to intersection of county road leading from Frying Pan to Herndon
- Hutchinson, L. E. May, 1891 (Box-folder RP-265)
  Change: road from Thompson's precinct enters road leading from Little River Turnpike to the Town of Herndon
- April, 1891 (Box-folder RP-266)
  Road commencing at Sanford Hutchinson's corner on Little River Turnpike to Braddock Road
- October, 1891 (Box-folder RP-267)
  Road from some point on the Little River Turnpike not more than two miles from Court House Building to Falls Church
- November, 1892 (Box-folder RP-268)
  Change: from Mero's store to Gum Spring
- June, 1892 (Box-folder RP-269)
  Road from River Road (Garner's Mill Road) to Georgetown and Leesburg Pike
- May, 1892 (Box-folder RP-270)
  Open portion of River Road (Garner's Mill Road) from Seneca Road to Loudoun and Fairfax Line
- November, 1892 (Box-folder RP-271)
  Road from at Red Hill to the Braddock Road at Salisbury Farm
- August, 1892 (Box-folder RP-272)
  Colchester Road over Pohick Run
- December, 1892 (Box-folder RP-273)
  Road leading from the Colchester Road to Payne's Church Road
- February, 1892 (Box-folder RP-274)
  Road entering the Court House by the Warrenton and Little River Turnpikes
- April, 1893 (Box-folder RP-274)
  Road from West End Catholic Church to the Corporation Limits of the Town of Falls Church
- RP-276 (Box-folder RP-276)
  Beginning in Wolf Run Shoals Road, at the Elgin School House...to Yates Ford Road
- January, 1893 (Box-folder RP-277)
  Road leading from the Colchester Road to Braddock Road
- January, 1893 (Box-folder RP-278)
  Extend county road from Woodyard's Precinct...to Ford's Mill Road
- July, 1893 (Box-folder RP-279)
  Road from Braddock Road near Accotink Run to Little River Turnpike over the old tavern
- August, 1894 (Box-folder RP-280)
  Discontinue portion of county road leading from Centreville to the Little River Turnpike
- August, 1894 (Box-folder RP-281)
  At the point on the old county road leading from Burke's Station to Lee Chapel...to a point 15 feet from Railroad land
- April, 1894 (Box-folder RP-281)
  At a point on the old county road leading from Burke's Station to Lee Chapel...to a point 15 feet from Railroad land
- November, 1894 (Box-folder RP-282)
  Road from Falls Church to Little River Turnpike
- April, 1895 (Box-folder RP-283)
  Widen Guinea Road near Burke's Station
- March, 1895 (Box-folder RP-284)
  From a point on the road leading from Herndon to the Ox Road...to a point on the road leading from Wiehle to the Lawyer's Road
- June, 1895 (Box-folder RP-285)
  Road leading from Freedom Hill to Middle Turnpike...to road from Freedom Hill to Walter's Mill
- October, 1895 (Box-folder RP-286)
  County road between the Court House and Ridge Road, beginning at Robert Mateers Lane and ending at a convenient point on Ridge Road
- May, 1895 (Box-folder RP-287)
  Road right of way from Collingwood Beach to the County Road
- February, 1896 (Box-folder RP-288)
  Change: Road from Old Union to Georgetown Turnpike, through the lands of Mrs. Carper and others, near Bethel Baptist Church
- May, 1896 (Box-folder RP-289)
  Road from point in the boundary line between Fairfax and the city of Alexandria...to a junction with the Middle (or Leesburg) Turnpike
- September, 1896 (Box-folder RP-290)
  Change: County Road from Clifton to Fairfax Station through the lands of R. Jones and the Poor house property (County of Fairfax land)
- September, 1896 (Box-folder RP-290)
  Change: county road from Clifton to Fairfax Station, through the lands of R. Jones and the Poor house property
- January, 1896 (Box-folder RP-291)
  Road survey of Schreaves Road leading to Falls Church
- February, 1896 (Box-folder RP-292)
  Change: Hampton Road, opposite the lands of Fairfax and Marshall
- September, 1897 (Box-folder RP-293)
  Road from Clifton to Yates Ford Road, through the lands of M. Hetzel, J. T. Pettitt, D. N. Robinson, C. F. Ford, and J. A. Marshall
- March, 1897 (Box-folder RP-294)
  Change: County road from Fairfax County Road, adjacent to land of N. F. Graham
- November, 1897 (Box-folder RP-295)
  Change: road leading from Sideburn Station to the Fairfax Station Road
- August, 1897 (Box-folder RP-296)
  Road from Gunston Road...to crossroads known as Negro Head
- November, 1898 (Box-folder RP-297)
  Outlet road in Lee District from Anbagen's farm to the Alexandria Road
- May, 1898 (Box-folder RP-298)
  County road from a point in the town of Wiehle on the line of the Southern Railway in the Dranesville District...to a point on the Ridge Road
- January, 1898 (Box-folder RP-299)
  Discontinue road from A and E Railway Company to the Rolling Road in the Lee District
- October, 1898 (Box-folder RP-300)
  Road from the lands of William R. Ward to Telegraph Station, through the lands of Mrs. Lee
- March, 1898 (Box-folder RP-301)
  Road from Clifton to Mr. Thomas Fenwick's land, intersecting with Colchester Road
- September, 1898 (Box-folder RP-302)
  Chapel Street in Clifton Station; extension eastward to Colchester Roll-way
- September, 1898 (Box-folder RP-302)
- July, 1898 (Box-folder RP-303)
  Road from Pohick Road...to the Keene's Mill Road
- September, 1898 (Box-folder RP-304)
  Road from the Falls Church and Court House Road to the "Hunter Road"
- October, 1898 (Box-folder RP-305)
  Change: road near Bone Mill Ridge over Accotink Run, from Whose Road to the new bridge
- December, 1898 (Box-folder RP-306)
  Relocate: County Road from Little River Turnpike to Edgar Scott's Residence
- November, 1898 (Box-folder RP-307)
  Point on county road near Ashton's leading from Little River Turnpike to Centreville to a point on the Warrenton Turnpike
- July, 1899 (Box-folder RP-308)
  Road from a point on the New Cut Road near Vale Post Office to Ox Road
- August, 1899 (Box-folder RP-309)
  Road from Braddock Road to Sagar Avenue near Fairfax Court House
- September, 1899 (Box-folder RP-310)
  Establish boundary lines of road leading from Faulkner's shop on Leesburg Turnpike to the residence of Joshua Kirby
- August, 1899 (Box-folder RP-311)
  Repair road leading from Ballston to Langley
- December, 1899 (Box-folder RP-312)
  County road on the boundary lines of Truitt, Payne, & McNair
- June, 1899 (Box-folder RP-313)
  Open private road to the public; the road at V. W. Lee's to the county road near Stuart's Mill
- January, 1900 (Box-folder RP-313)
  Road from the point on the Braddock Road to a point on the Guinea Road
- January, 1900 (Box-folder RP-315)
  Road from Luis Corner to a point on a road from Fairfax to Vienna, opposite or near the road running to Falls Church
- June, 1900 (Box-folder RP-316)
  Outlet road beginning at the corner of the Wooster tract, along the Van Gorder tract to the Magner Road
- December, 1901 (Box-folder RP-317)
  Change: public road leading from Jermantown to Oakton
- March, 1901 (Box-folder RP-318)
  Road from the Telegraph Road to Franconia Station
- March, 1902 (Box-folder RP-319)
  Change: Straighten point on Hampton Road in front of residence of H. E. Bradley through the lands of H. E. Bradley
- June, 1902 (Box-folder RP-320)
  Change: Public road from Jermantown to Waples on Millard's Mill
- November, 1902 (Box-folder RP-321)
  Road from the lands of Percy Cranford to Gunston Road, including building a bridge over Keans Creek
- November, 1902 (Box-folder RP-322)
  Road from Leesburg Turnpike near Munson's Hill to a point on the public road from Mt. Olivet Church to the Falls Church to the Falls Church and Georgetown Turnpike
- November, 1902 (Box-folder RP-323)
  Discontinue a road
- July, 1902 (Box-folder RP-324)
  Road leading from Lorton Valley Post Office...to the Colchester Public Road
- September, 1902 (Box-folder RP-325)
  Change: Road leading from Lewinsville to Chesterbrook
- April, 1902 (Box-folder RP-326)
  Change: Telegraph Road along Accotink Run north of Pohick Church
- September, 1902 (Box-folder RP-327)
  Establish boundary lines of County road leading from Core's corner on the Alexandria Pike to Lewinsville
- March, 1902 (Box-folder RP-328)
  Outlet road from land of Charles H. Smith to Riverside Park Road
- November, 1902 (Box-folder RP-329)
  Road leading from Sideburn Station to the new cut road where it intersects with Old Braddock Road
- November, 1903 (Box-folder RP-330)
  Road across the bed of a lake or pond in the Town of Wiehle
- May, 1903 (Box-folder RP-331)
  Road from section of Ball's Hill...following the general course of the old Army Road and intersecting with Langley - Lewinsville Road
- April, 1903 (Box-folder RP-332)
  Road from Mount Vernon Road between the City of Alexandria and Mount Vernon to Telegraph Road
- January, 1903 (Box-folder RP-333)
  Road leading from Yates Ford Road to a point near Lewis Woodyards
- May, 1903 (Box-folder RP-334)
  Road from Accotink Station to Accotink Village to a point on the northwest side of Telegraph Road at or near the corner of the lands of Nevitt and Higham
- August, 1903 (Box-folder RP-335)
  Road from point on Sawyers Road to Hunter's Mill Crossing on the S. R. Way
- September, 1903 (Box-folder RP-336)
  Change: road and overhead bridge at Fairfax Station
- March, 1903 (Box-folder RP-337)
  Road from a point on the Rolling Road at the corner between Young and Javin's farms to the Braddock Road
- September, 1903 (Box-folder RP-338)
  Change: Road at Pohick Station
- September, 1904 (Box-folder RP-339)
  Change: Public Road at Herbert's Crossing
- May, 1904 (Box-folder RP-340)
  Change/Establish road at Southern Railway Crossing at Burke's Station
- January, 1904 (Box-folder RP-341)
  Change: Road leading from Hunter's Mill to Freedom Hill
- RP-342 (Box-folder RP-342)
  Change/Establish: Road at Accotink Station in the Mount Vernon District
- January, 1904 (Box-folder RP-343)
  Change: Road near Lorton through lands of John Plaskett
- September, 1904 (Box-folder RP-344)
  Road from Fords Mill Road to the Yates Ford Road
- November, 1905 (Box-folder RP-345)
  Change: Country Road through lands of Charles Cutts
- September, 1905 (Box-folder RP-346)
  Change:'Talbert' Road to line between Martin and Kilbourn to the Railroad Station
- December, 1905 (Box-folder RP-347)
  Road from Georgetown and Leesburg Turnpike to Great Falls on the Potomac River
- September, 1906 (Box-folder RP-348)
  Repair River Road near Riverside and Hunter's in Alexandria
- November, 1906 (Box-folder RP-349)
  Road from Brown's Mill...to a point on Hunter Mill Road
- May, 1906 (Box-folder RP-350)
  Road across Creed's land to Bailey's Crossroads to Theological Seminary Road
- June, 1906 (Box-folder RP-351)
  Change: Little River Turnpike bridge near Alexandria; over the stream on the road running from Little River Turnpike over Annandale to Falls Church, in the Falls Church District
- September, 1906 (Box-folder RP-352)
  Change: County Road from the Warrenton Pike to Pleasant Valley
- May, 1907 (Box-folder RP-353)
  Discontinue road running from Fairfax Falls Church Road near Merrifield to Little River Turnpike near Davis' Store & Horace Gibson's shop
- May, 1907 (Box-folder RP-354)
  Discontinue county road from Little River Turnpike to point on Fairfax- Falls Church Road
- March, 1907 (Box-folder RP-355)
  Road from Oakton, VA running west to a point on Vale Road near Montgomery
- March, 1907 (Box-folder RP-356)
  Road starting from the corner of Robert Wrenn on the Centreville and Chantilly Road...to the Braddock Road
- January, 1908 (Box-folder RP-357)
  Road from site of old Fairfax Station to the new Fairfax Station (Lee District)
- Unknown (Box-folder RP-358)
  Occoquan Road